AMOGH MISRA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A high-energy student currently finalizing a bachelor's degree in Computer Science and prepared to contribute abilities to Internship roles while further developing acquired skills and gaining real-world experience. Highly organized, responsible, and well-versed in **Python and C++**. Positively impact **Machine Learning, Web Development,** and **Big Data** operations with top-notch communication and critical thinking skills.

WORK HISTORY

Wynk Music (Gurugram) – Internship (Jun 2020 – Jul 2020)

- Meta-Data enrichment by application of various models to improve the tags of songs
- Built Neural Network models to predict the mood of a particular song and suggest others of a similar kind
- Also built models to predict the appropriate genre of a particular song and suggesting others of a similar kind.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

SMO using MapReduce: Jan 2020 – Jun 2020

- Github Repository
- Parallelization of Spider Monkey Optimization Algorithm is performed to get better and more accurate results when dealing with a huge amount of data in less time
- Random initialization of the population variables is done, and other decision variables are used to determine the results
- The platform used: Hadoop along with HDFS (Hadoop Distributed File System), MapReduce architecture, and Python

THE THIRD EYE: Jul 2019 - Jan 2020

- GithubRepository
- Project to simplify the lives of visually impaired people by helping them to live their dream life
- Trained the model based on Inception v4 methodology on a dataset
- Created a web-app using Tensorflow.js which helped in implementing the trained model

STRING PLAYGROUND: Feb 2019 - Apr 2019

- GithubRepository
- Image classification is applied for string recognition and then the text recognized is subjected to string matching algorithms like KMP algorithm, etc.
- Python is used for the code and Keras library for image recognition and then tested on MNIST dataset

FRIEND FINDER: Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

- GithubRepository
- A social media website consisting of special features like friend suggestions, posting pictures or videos It included the algorithm of predicting "People you may know" through user's friend list
- Developed using CSS, PHP, JAVASCRIPT and then run and tested on the XAMPP server.

PAYTEZZ: Aug 2018 - Oct 2018

- GithubRepository
- An e-wallet with features like checking bank-balance, two-tier security for every transaction, adding or paying money to another user, etc.
- Coded using C++ while using File Data structure as the data structure to store all data requirements

Gesture Controlled Snake: Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

- Github Repository
- Snake Game, played via hand gestures
- This is a Java based simple game of Snake, which uses Machine learning and Neural Networks to recognise hand gestures in live video using Keras and Python.
- And performing the said task after image recognition.

SKILLS

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Machine Learning
- Data Analytics
- C/C++Programming
- Java
- Python
- HTML, JavaScript, PHP
- Database Management System (DBMS) and SQL
- Hadoop, MapReducePrograming
- OpenCV Essentia, Keras, Tensoflow
- English Proficiency

EDUCATION

TRAINING – Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence Coding Blocks (Offline) – (June 2019 – July 2019)

- Certificate link
- 6 week offline course consisting of Data Science and Machine Learning algorithms, followed by Neural Networks and Image processing projects, and Knowledge about Open Source projects was covered

B. Tech (Hons.), Computer Science (2017 - 2021) JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATIONTECHNOLOGY

• CGPA: 7.9/10

XII (Senior Secondary), Science Year of Completion:

CBSE Board (Study Hall Lucknow)

Percentage: 89.40%

X (Secondary)

Year of Completion: 2015

CBSE Board (Study Hall Lucknow)

• CGPA: 9.8

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

 Completed JP Morgan's Software Engineering Virtual Experience internship. Certificate Link